

IRINA DELAMARE

CRI STUDENT UNIVERSITÉ DE PARIS

I am a hardworking and volunteer third-year bachelor student at CRI with internships experiences who want to become a researcher and study birds using powerful innovating Technics and computing, working at the frontier of evolutionary biology, ecology, behavioral and morphofunctionnal biology, paleobiology and systematic, focussing on biodiversity in its globality.





+33 6 40 69 22 06



38 Rue Mathis, 75019 Paris, France



irina.delamare@cri-paris.org irina.delamare@gmail.com





www.linkedin.com/in/irinadelamare/

INTERNSHIPS

All my internship reports are accessible on my GitHub account

SORBONNE UNIVERSITY - 2021-03 TO 2021-05 EVOLUTIONARY ECOLOGY OF EUROPEAN TITS WITH CLOTILDE BIARD

• Field placement following the evolution of Great and Blue tits nests

MUSÉUM NATIONAL D'HISTOIRE NATURELLE - 2021-01 TO 2021-03 MASCARENE MARTIN PHYLOGENY WITH BEN WARREN

- Phylogenetic study of Mascarene martins populations.
- Lab work : DNA extraction, PCR amplification, electrophoresis, data analysis in Geneious, phylogenetic tree reconstruction.

CENTRE DE RECHERCHE INTERDISCIPLINAIRE - 2020-09 TO 2021-01 BIRDSONG TEAM WITH PAULINE PROVINI

- Understand the mechanisms by which birds are producing vocalizations.
- Gathering and analysing data using R programming language.

KING'S COLLEGE LONDON - 2019-06 TO 2019-07
DEVELOPMENTAL NEUROBIOLOGY WITH RICHARD WINGATE

- Study of cerebellum developments in reptiles.
- Lab work : Nissl staining, Immunohistochemistry staining, Golgi staining.

SKILLS

- Bilingual English → Cambridge Certificate in Advanced English & IELTS C1
- Computing in Python, R and Shell programming language
- Teamwork, lateral thinking and communication

EDUCATION

PARIS DESCARTES UNIVERSITY - CRI: F.D.V PROGRAM - BACHELOR Expected Graduation: June 2021

SCIENTIFIC BACCALAUREATE - BAC S MENTION BIEN 2018 - Bac Scientifique, spécialité Sciences et Vie de la Terre

EXPERIENCES

SICB - PRESENTATION AT INTERNATIONNAL CONFERENCE CYCLE 2021-01 TO 2021-02

- 6 min talk on the morpho-functional study of birds vocal system, discussing the influence of phylogeny on acoustic parameters.
- First author of an abstract that sum up my 5 months internship with Pauline Provini (avalaible here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pc85poM5rC0)

YNHSM - 2 TIME'S OBSERVER AT CONFERENCE CYCLE - 2017 AND 2018

• Followed the conference cycle as a young interested High-school student

OLYMPIADES DE GÉOSCIENCES - FIRST LAUREATE OF MY ESTABLISHMENT - 2017

MOOC EDX 2019 - "IELTS ACADEMIC TEST PREPARATION"

MOOC COURSERA 2017 - "DINO 101 : DINOSAURS PALEOBIOLOGY"

MOOC COURSERA 2017 - "PALEONTOLOGY : THEROPOD DINOSAURS AND THE ORIGIN OF BIRDS"

GAME MASTER - IMMERSIA ESCAPE GAME PARIS - 2019-10 TO ONGOING

Acting abilities and training as an entertainer.

ONE WEEK INTERNSHIPS

MUSÉUM NATIONAL D'HISTOIRE NATURELLE - 2019-02 - UMR ISYEB WITH MARC ELEAUME

Pictures shooting and Data sorting.

MUSÉUM NATIONAL D'HISTOIRE NATURELLE - 2019-01 - UMR ISYEB WITH AURÉLIEN MIRALLES

• Collect data, identify and sort lizard specimens.

MUSÉUM NATIONAL D'HISTOIRE NATURELLE - 2018-02 - UMR BOREA WITH MARC ELEAUME

• Pictures shooting of starfish specimens.

GROUPE ORNITHOLOGIQUE ET NATURALISTE DU NORD PAS DE CALAIS 2015-04

• Birds and insects identification.

COMPUTING EXPERIENCES

All my computing experiencies are accessible on my GitHub account

PYTHON

Modelisation, problem solving, knowledge of Jupyter Notebook, uses of library like *Matplotlib, NumPy, Pandas, Gensim...*

R

Data analysis, statistical computing, data visualization, sound analysis, phylogenetic tree construction, knowledge of Rstudio, uses of library like *ggplot2*, *tidyverse*, *here*, *warbleR*, *dplyr*, *soundgen*...

GIT

Basic usage of working with repositories (Clone, add, commit, push, pull, status ...)

BASH

Basic usage of bash command line on terminal for file system and programming tools